# João Duarte

jaduarte1998@gmail.com · www.joaoavduarte.tech · www.linkedin.com/in/joaoavduarte/

# Education

#### Bachelor in Videogames and Multimedia

Lisbon, PT

Universidade Lusófona de Humanidades e Tecnologias

Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2021

EQF level 4 in Programming and Management of Computer Systems

Lisbon, PT

Escola Profissional Bento de Jesus Caraça

Sep. 2014 - Aug. 2017

#### Experience

# VivaDrive | Software Developer / Computer Vision Intern Python

Warsaw, PL

Oct. 2020 - Feb. 2021

- Developing the automatic detection and localization of captured footage on the 3D space using open source SLAM and point cloud registration algorithms
- Developing the image recognition of captured footage to detect specific objects using Yolo v4
- Documenting and testing the previous and ongoing development
- Working directly with external client Vinçotte and using agile methodologies

### Siemens | Software Developer Intern

Lisbon, PT

Ionic, Cordova, Angular, NodeJS, Java/Spring and SQL

Apr. 2017 - Jul. 2017

- Developed a native and hybrid mobile application demo for in-house use as an Event and Conference management
- Designed project requirements in cooperation with team lead
- Tested application in various platforms and devices to ensure compatibility and responsiveness

#### Siemens | Test Automation Intern

Lisbon, PT

Java, Cucumber/Gherkin, JBehave and Maven

Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2016

- Updated and developed automated tests for internal programs that helped reduce testing time
- Participated in project meetings with technical staff, members and external clients

Attended and participated in several tech events in the industry.

# Skills

Languages: C#, Java, C / C++, JavaScript, SQL, HTML / CSS, Python

Technologies: Git, Linux, Ionic, Angular, JBehave, NodeJS, Spring

Others: Unity, Unreal, Office, Photoshop, Maya, Atlassian Tools, LaTeX

Languages

Portuguese: Native Spanish: Conversational

English: Fluent French: Basic

#### Profile

I'm a polyvalent, analytical and hard-working programmer with a practical "get the things done" approach, who always thrives to achieve the best results.

I enjoy creating things that allow me to think outside the box, like videogames and applications, using a wide variety of technologies. My goal is to learn a lot and provide great experiences.

Currently I intend on beginning my career as a Junior Developer and Junior Game Programmer in the tech industry, while pursuing a Master's degree in Computer Science.

#### Hobbies and Interests

Reenacting
Games and Technology

Historical European Martial Arts Travelling